Litchfield Female Academy Collection
Litchfield Historical Society
Litchfield Female Academy Collection
1787-1927
Litchfield Historical Society 7 South Street, P.O. Box 385 Litchfield, CT, 6759 URL: http://www.litchfieldhistoricalsociety.org/archon Email: archivist@litchfieldhistoricalsociety.org Phone: 860-567-4501 Fax: 860-567-3565
Pierce, Sarah, 1767-1852; Brace, John Pierce, 1793-1872; Litchfield Historical Society; Vanderpoel, Emily Noyes, 1842-1939
11.67
This collection documents the history of The Litchfield Female Academy, Litchfield, Connecticut. Early records refer to the Academy as Miss Pierce's School, Miss Pierce's Academy, and Sarah Pierce's Academy. In the collection are institutional records; correspondence, diaries, journals, school notebooks, and albums of students; papers of Sarah Pierce and the Pierce family; and correspondence of Emily Noyes Vanderpoel regarding her research for her books "Chronicles of a Pioneer School, from 1792 to 1833", published in 1903 and "More Chronicles of a Pioneer School" published in 1927. Included in the institutional records are works written by Sarah Pierce and her nephew, John Pierce Brace.
1890-07-2
Biographical Note
Sarah Pierce was born in Litchfield, Connecticut on June 26, 1767, the youngest of the 7 children of Mary (Paterson) and John Pierce. Her mother died when she was 3 years old and her father remarried. At the death of her father, when she was fourteen, Sarah and her sister Nancy went to New York City for a formal education. In 1792 she started teaching girls in her home and by 1798 the school became so successful that an Academy building was built. Her nephew John Pierce Brace became the director in 1827, but she continued to teach, focusing on her favorite subject - history. Sarah Pierce died in Litchfield on Jan. 19, 1852 and was buried in the West Burying Ground
Scope and Contents
This collection documents the history of The Litchfield Female Academy, Litchfield, Connecticut. Early records refer to the Academy as Miss Pierce's School, Miss Pierce's Academy, and Sarah Pierce's Academy. In the collection are institutional records; correspondence, diaries, journals, school notebooks, and albums of students; papers of Sarah Pierce and the Pierce family; and correspondence of Emily Noyes Vanderpoel regarding her research for her books "Chronicles of a Pioneer School, from 1792 to 1833", published in 1903 and "More Chronicles of a Pioneer School" published in 1927. Included in the institutional records are works written by Sarah Pierce and her nephew, John Pierce Brace.
Arrangement of Materials
The collection is arranged in 4 series:
Series 1. Litchfield Female Academy Institutional Records
Series 2. Student Paper, Records, and Documents
Series 3. Pierce Family Papers
Series 4. Emily Noyes Vanderpoel Papers
This collection has been assembled from 3 collections: Litchfield Female Academy, Sarah Pierce, and Emily Noyes Vanderpoel. These collections had been assembled, re-assembled, and intermingled over many years with additions from many donors [see Acquisition Information -Accruals/Additions].
Related Materials
Benjamin Tallmadge Collection, Pierce Family Correspondence, Reeve Collection, Wolcott Family Collection, Elihu Harrison Business Papers, Grant Papers.
Information about related materials is available at http://www.litchfieldhistoricalsociety.org
Separated Materials
Catalogues for 1824, 1825, 1826 & 1830 are housed in an oversize box.
Daguerreotypes and photographs of portraits of Sarah Pierce, Mary Pierce, John Brace Pierce and other Pierce family members are shelved in separate boxes.
Framed documents housed in Curatorial Center.
Index Terms
This Collection is indexed under the following controlled access subject terms.
Corporate Name:
Litchfield Female Academy (Conn.)
Genre/Form of Material:
Account books; Autograph albums; Correspondence; Diaries; Exercise books; Notebooks; Receipts; Rewards of merit
Geographic Name:
Litchfield (Conn.) -- History
Personal Name:
Brace, John Pierce, 1793-1872; Pierce, Sarah, 1767-1852
Topical Term:
Private schools - Connecticut - Litchfield - History; Schools; Women - Education - Connecticut - Litchfield - History
Conditions Governing Access
The collection is open for research.
Alternate Formats Available
Transcriptions are available for some documents.
Additional information is avaliable at http://www.litchfieldhistoricalsociety.org
Acquisition Information
The materials were acquired by Litchfield Historical Society from Gray, Jane (Loring), Mrs. Asa on 01/01/1890.
Accruals
Gifts from Charles Mansfield (1890); Mrs. John A. Vanderpoel (1900); Dwight C. Kilbourn (1900); Miss Lewis (1911); Edgar Van Winkle (1913); Mrs. Morris Seymour (1914); Mrs. Edward Seymour (1916); Dr. John Buel (1916; Cornelia Rankin (1920); Lucy Brace Sadikoff (1920); Gertrude E. Welch (1920); Kate E. Westbrook (1928); Marcus Reynolds (1933); Mrs. VanWinkle (1943); Jane G. Cooke(1947); Elizabeth M. Hall (1950); Mrs. James Woodruff (1953); Dorothy Johnson (1954); Mrs. Floyd Vanderpoel (1954); Eaton Jone estate (1971); William Warren (1973); Mrs. Richard Brickley (1981); Museum purchase (1982); Mr. & Mrs. C. Minor Barringer (1993); Doris Townsend (1998); Chris Sinacola (2000); Mr. and Mrs. Malcolm Bramley (2005); Charles Stookey (2006).
Other Information
Material objects related to the Litchfield Female Academy include needlework, watercolors, watchpapers, maps, items belonging to Sarah Pierce, etc. Contact the Museum Curator for further information.
This collection was processed with support from the Council on Library and Information Resources (CLIR).
Additional information may be found at http://www.litchfieldhistoricalsociety.org
Detailed Description of the Collection
- Litchfield Female Academy Institutional Records
  - [Accounts], 1827-1828 (Folder 1)
    James Winship's account for building supplies for the Academy building
  - [Accounts], 1830-1856 (Folder 2)
    Trustees note to Miss Pierce
  - [Accounts], 1846-1854 (Folder 3)
    Litchfield Female Academy accounts per J.G. Beckwith, Treasurer.
  - [Accounts], 1854-1856 (Folder 4)
    Litchfield Female Academy accounts per H.W. Buel, Treasurer
  - Bills and receipts (Folder 5)
    4 undated bills: payment to Miss Mary Pierce for the note she holds against the Corporation; to Leonard Goodwin for sundries building the Academy; to E.B. Smith for rope, glass, etc.; and list of bills paid by J.G. Beckwith.
  - Bills and receipts, 1828 (Folder 7)
  - Bills and receipts, 1829-1834 (Folder 8)
  - Bills and receipts, 1852-1854 (Folder 9)
  - Bills and receipts, 1855-1856 (Folder 10)
  - Catalogue of the Ladies Academy in Litchfield, 1818 (Folder 11)
    Handwritten "Catalogue of the young ladies members of the Ladies Academy in Litchfield in the year 1818." dated 29 Oct. 1818 by J. A. Shepard.
  - Catalogue of the Litchfield Academy, 1830 (Folder 12)
    List of students (girls and boys) for 1830 winter term, commencing on Nov. 24.
  - Connecticut. General Assembly, May 1863 (Folder 13)
    Resolution amending the Litchfield Female Academy Charter of May 1854.
  - Diplomas (Folder 14)
  - Penmanship (Folder 15)
    3 samples of student penmanship lessons
  - Promissary note, 1828 Apr 15 (Folder 16)
    Promissary note to William Buel signed by Leonard Goodwin, James Brace and [Jonathan] R. Landon.
  - Prospectus, 1832 (Folder 17)
    Outline of courses, books used, tuition, rules of governance, etc.
  - Prospectus, 1841 (Folder 18)
    List of trustees & instructors with outline of tuition, terms, boarding, courses of instruction.
  - Pierce, Sarah (Folder 19)
    "Moralistic essay and anecdote". undated.
    Includes transcript.
  - Pierce, Sarah, 1833 (Folder 20)
    Album. "Grandmother's Tales"
  - Pierce, Sarah (Folder 21)
    Manuscript for "Ruth", a play by Sarah Pierce
  - Pierce, Sarah (Folder 22)
    Manuscript for "Two Cousins", a play by Sarah Pierce.
  - Rules for the School and Family, 1814 (Folder 23)
    rules for attending Miss Pierce's School. Together with the names and hometowns of the young ladies attending the school in the summer of 1814
  - Rules of Miss Pierce's School, 1818 May 19 (Folder 24)
    18 rules of Miss Pierce's School in 1818.
  - Rules, 1819 (Folder 25)
    A few of the school rules in 1819.
  - Rules of Litchfield Female Academy, 1826 (Folder 26)
    23 rules. Includes a transcript.
  - Shepherd, Levi (Folder 27)
    License for John Brace to build Shepherd's Improved Fire-Place.
  - Stock Certificates, 1827 (Folder 28)
    Two undated stock certificates for capital Stock of the Litchfield Female Academy, signed by Frederick Wolcott, President.
    Stock Certificates dated 1827: No. 19 (one share) to Origen Seymour; No. 29 (two shares) to Samuel Buel; No. 32 (One share) to Sylvester Galpin. All signed by Frederick Wolcott, President and John P. Brace, Secretary.
  - Subscribers to build a Schoolhouse for Female Academy, 1798 Mar 10 (Folder 29)
    List of subscribers and amount pledged to build a schoolhouse on Miss Sally Pierce's land.
  - Litchfield Female Academy - Illustrations (Folder 30)
    Copies of drawings of the Litchfield Female Academy building.
    1 - View of the Litchfield Academy attributed to [ ] Gimbrede, circa 1830.
    1 - Postcard reproduction by Benedict, Litchfield, Conn. of a drawing by Emily Noyes Vanderpoel.
  - Record Book, 1827-1856 (Folder 31)
    Record Book for the Litchfield Female Academy includes list of subscribers, copy of the act of incorporation, and minutes of meetings.
  - Record Book, 1827-1856 (Folder 32)
    Treasurer's book of accounts
  - Brace, John Pierce, 1814 (Folder 33)
    "A copy of an Address delivered at the close of the School in the Summer of 1814 by Mr. John Brace." A handwritten copy by Nancy Holmes, a student at LFA in 1814, dated 4 July 1814.
  - Brace, John Pierce, 1814-1830 (Folder 34)
    Journal - "Private journal for 1814 in Northhampton, Litchfield, etc. List of plants in Herbarium, given to Williams College."
  - Brace, John Pierce, 1815-1857 (Folder 35)
    Journal - "Private journal 1815, written at Litchfield, Conn. Lists of Conn. officers for 1816-1857 inclusive"
  - Brace, John Pierce, 1816-1817 (Folder 36)
    Journal - "Miscellaneous vol. III: Lectures on Philosophy; Verses; Address 1816; Heads of papers 1816; Lectures on astronomy in Africa; Heads of papers 1817; List of pupils 1817.
  - Brace, John, 1819-1822 (Folder 37)
    Album- "Miscellanies, vol. mineralogy; heads of papers 1819-1822; lists school [etc]
  - Brace, John Pierce, 1822-1827 (Folder 38)
    Album - School catalogues, prose, addresses, etc.
  - Brace, John, 1850 (Folder 39)
    Album- "History of my poetry volume I" 1850 Sep 3-21. Notes on his poetry written 1805-1811.
  - Brace, John Pierce, 1850 (Folder 40)
    "History of my poetry Volume II" 1850 Sep 23-Oct 16. Notes on his poetry written 1812-1821.
  - Brace, John Pierce, 1850 (Folder 41)
    "History of my poetry Volume III" 1850 Oct. 16-31. Notes on his poetry written 1821-1824.
  - Brace, John Pierce, 1850-1854 (Folder 42)
    "History of my poetry. Volume IV the end: Anachronisms; A tale, Roaring Brook" 1850 Oct 31 - 1854 Aug 30. Notes on his poetry written 1824-1831 with an index to Vol. I-IV. Also other writing.
  - Brace, John Pierce, 1854 (Folder 43)
    Notebook - "Roaring Brook: a tale of the past"
    [This is continued in "History of my Poetry Vol. IV".]
  - Brace, John Pierce, 1853-1854 (Folder 44)
    Notebook - "Search for a Hero: a tale of the war of 1812, vol. I"
  - Brace, John Pierce, 1853-1854 (Folder 45)
    Notebook - "Search for a Hero: a tale of the war of 1812, vol. II"
  - Catalogue of the Litchfield Academy, 1816
    Catalogue of the members of the female academy for the Summer 1816 term. Framed, located in off-site storage. Advance notice required for viewing.
- Student Papers, Records, and Documents
  This series is arranged alphabetically by the married name of the student, if known. For unmarried or unknown married surnames, by family name.
  - Anonymous, 1815 Jul-1818 Jan (Folder 1)
    Journal of an anonymous student. On title page is written "litchfield Connecticut, July 28, 1815,at Miss Pierce Academy, Lictfield"
  - Atwater,Jonathan, 1797 Mar 25 (Folder 2)
    Letter to Mr. and Mrs. Atwater dated Litchfield (Conn.) 1797 Mar 25.
  - Bartlett, Martha Anne, 1824 (Folder 3)
    These have been transferred to the Museum Curator - Note to John Pierce Brace with 3 watchpapers.
  - Bassett, Mary, 1829 (Folder 4)
    Album
  - Bassett, Mary, 1833 (Folder 5)
    Diary
  - Bassett, Mary (Folder 6)
    Handwriting samples
  - Bassett, Mary (Folder 7)
    Rules for script writing
  - Bassett, Mary (Folder 8)
    The Misses Bassett's School for Young Ladies, Auburn, NY [1832]
  - Beach, Lucy (Sheldon), Mrs. Theron, 1802-1803 (Folder 9)
    Journal
  - Beach, Lucy (Sheldon), Mrs. Theron, 1802-1803 (Folder 10)
    Photocopy of 1802-1803 Journal
  - Beach, Lucy (Sheldon), Mrs. Theron, 1803 (Folder 11)
    Lucy Sheldon's Journal for Winter 1803, continues her 1802-1803 Journal
  - Beach, Lucy (Sheldon), Mrs. Theron, 1802 (Folder 12)
  - Beach, Lucy (Sheldon), Mrs. Theron, 1802 (Folder 13)
    Copy book of school lessons
  - Beach, Lucy (Sheldon), Mrs. Theron, 1802 (Folder 14)
    Typed transcript of 1802 copy book of school lessons.
  - Beckman, Sarah, 1807 May 17-Aug (Folder 15)
  - Benedict, Charlotte H. Newman (Mrs. Abijah) (Folder 16)
    Journal circa 1810
  - Bolles, Roxana (Clark), Mrs. Samuel, 1822 (Folder 17)
    Photocopies and transcripts of 2 letters to her cousin Sophia Griswold dated Litchfield 2 Mar 1822 and 26 Jul 1822 with news of church, friends, and family.
  - Bolles, Roxana (Clark), Mrs. Samuel, 1823 Oct 20 (Folder 18)
    Photocopy and transcript of a letters to her sister Sophia Clark, with an added letter to her cousin Sophia, includes news of family and friends.
  - Buell, Lois Ann (Folder 19)
    [Reward of Merit] Good Examination card. undated circa 1825-1830
  - Buel, Maria, 1829-1830 (Folder 20)
    Notebook 1829 Dec 3 - 1830 Mar 4 contains penmanship and writing lessons
  - Buel, Mary T (Folder 21)
    Diploma
  - Butler, Eliza A. (Ogden), Mrs. Charles, 1816-1818 (Folder 22)
    Transcript "The Journal of Eliza A. Ogden; written while at Boarding School in Litchfield, Conn. 1816-1818"
  - Butler, Eliza A. (Ogden), Mrs. Charles, 1817 Apr 4 (Folder 23)
    Letter to Eliza Ogden in Walton, NY from Sarah Finkle, Nancy Waldo and Minerva Finkle sent from Litchfield, Conn. with news of friends and school.
  - Butler, Eliza A. (Ogden), Mrs. Charles, 1818 Sep 11 (Folder 24)
    Letter to Eliza A. Ogden in Walton, NY from Adaline St. John and Juliana Shepard in Litchfield, Conn.
  - Butler, Eliza A. (Ogden), Mrs. Charles, 1820 Jan 12 (Folder 25)
    Letter to Eliza A. Ogden in Walton, NY from Emily C. Niles in West Stockbridge, Mass.
  - Butler, Eliza A. (Ogden), Mrs. Charles, 1820 May 31 (Folder 26)
    Letter to Eliza A. Ogden in Walton, NY from Mrs. E. H. Westcot in [Saratoga Springs, NY] with news of friends and Miss Pierce.
  - Butler, Eliza A. (Ogden), Mrs. Charles, 1817-1820 (Folder 27)
    Transcripts of letters to Eliza A. Ogden, dated 1817 Apr 4; 1818 Sep 11; 1820 May 31.
  - Butler, [Mary?], 1819 Oct 26 (Folder 28)
    Receipt to Miss Butler for tuition and school expenses, signed by S. Pierce. On back is written "Mary's schooling"
  - Child, Mary A, 1820 (Folder 29)
    "Journal" dated Litchfield May 21, 1820 and continues through Aug 27, 1820.
  - Child, Mary A, 1820 (Folder 30)
    Transcript of her"Journal" dated Litchfield May 21 - Aug 27, 1820
  - Clark, Maria Amelia, 1827-1831 (Folder 31)
    7 letters to Sarah Deming in Wethersfield/Newington from Maria Amelia Clark Litchfield, Wethersfield, and Westfield with news of Litchfield, friends and family.
  - Clark, Maria Amelia, 1827-1831 (Folder 32)
    Transcripts of 7 letters to Sarah Deming in Wethersfield/Newington from Maria Amelia Clark Litchfield, Wethersfield, and Westfield with news of Litchfield, friends and family.
  - Collins, Cynthia (Painter), Mrs. Simeon (Folder 33)
    Photograph of Mrs. Simeon Collins on her 86th birthday. She was a student in 1806-1807.
    Photograph of an embroidery done while she was at LFA in 1807.
  - Cone, Elizabeth (Folder 34)
    3 Rewards of merit to Miss Elizabeth Cone: 1 small card for Good Behaviour, 1 small card Class of Good Scholars, and 1 large elaborate certificate "... for her attention to studies and good behavior in school by her teacher, A. Welch", dated 1829
  - Cooke, Elizabeth M. (Catlin), Mrs. Randall, 1813-1815 (Folder 35)
    Autograph "Memory Book" dated on the inside front cover 3 Oct 1815.
  - Cooke, Elizabeth/Betsy M. (Catlin), Mrs. Randall (Folder 36)
    Photograph of her at age 70.
  - Corey, Clara H, 1812 May 22 (Folder 37)
    Letter to John P. Brace dated Cooperstown, NY with news of her leaving Litchfield, life in Cooperstown, and inquiries about friends in Litchfield. Also transcript of letter.
  - Cowles, Julia, 1797-1803 (Folder 38)
    Photocopy of "The diaries of Julia Cowles: Published New Haven, CT, Yale University Press, 1931. She was a student at LFA in 1797.
  - Davenport, Miss [et al], 1818 Nov 1 (Folder 39)
    Letter dated from New Haven from 9 LFA students to John Brace requesting that he accept a gift of books
  - Deming, Lucretia (Folder 40)
    Diploma [undated]. Lucretia was a student at LFA in 1816, 1818-1819.
  - Dodge, Julia (Chittenden), Mrs. James Ross, 1802 Apr 21 (Folder 41)
    Reward of Merit for maps, paintings and other pieces at an exhibition by the young ladies of Miss Pierce's Academy.
  - Dodge, Julia (Chittenden), Mrs. James Ross (Folder 42)
    Photograph of a portrait of her.
  - Galpin, Clarissa (Smith), Mrs. Sylvester, 1814 (Folder 43)
    Album "A collection of interesting pieces to be perused at a leisure hour. 1814"
  - Gardiner, Julianna M. (McLachlan), Mrs. David, 1813 Aug 3 (Folder 44)
    Letter from Brunswick [Canada] to Miss Jane P. Brace at Miss Pierce's boarding school with news and inquiries about friends.
  - Gay, Sarah (Folder 45)
    Transcripts of 2 letters: Sarah Ann Ransom dated Litchfield 29 Sep 1815 to her cousin Sara Gay; and Sara Gay dated Litchfield 24 Jun 1826 to her cousin Margaret B. Gay in Sharon. Sarah Ann Ransom was a LFA student in 1815 and Sara Gay was there in 1826.
  - Grant, Harriet L (Folder 46)
    Album with school lessons and penmanship exercises. Includes "Chronological table of the most remarkable events from the peace of Paris in 1763 to the present time [1829]. Harriet was a LFA student 1829-1831.
  - Grant, Harriet, 1829,1831 (Folder 47)
    Receipts for tuition & school expenses dated 20 Apr 1829 signed by John P. Brace, and 19 Apr 1831 signed by L.E. Brace.
  - Grant, Harriet (Folder 48)
    Diploma for The Litchfield Female Academy, undated. Harriet was a LFA student 1829-1831.
  - Hale, Nancy, 1802 Sep (Folder 50)
    Transcript of letter dated Litchfield to her sisters and addressed to Miss Hannah Hale in Glastonbury with description of life at Miss Pierce's school.
  - Heminway, Mary Ann (Buel), Mrs. Merritt (Folder 51)
    Litchfield Female Academy undated. Mary Ann was a student at LFA in 1821.
  - Hollenbeck, Emily (Lindsley), Mrs. George W., 1811 Feb 11 (Folder 52)
    Receipt to Miss Lindsley for tuition and school expenses signed by M. Pierce. Includes transcript.
  - Hollenbeck, Emily (Lindsley), Mrs. George W., 1811 Oct (Folder 53)
    Receipt to Miss Emily Lindsley for boarding & use of horse signed by David L. Parmelee. Includes transcript
  - Hollenbeck, Emily (Lindsley), Mrs. George W. [et al], circa 1811 (Folder 54)
    Letter to Jerusha Lindsley in Albany dated Litchfield Dec 4 with notes from 7 LFA students.
  - Hunt, Mary Ann (Wadhams), Mrs. Hiram, 1895 Oct 7 (Folder 55)
    Letter dated Beloit, WI to George M. Woodruff acknowledging his letter and regrets that she cannot identify any of the silhouettes of girls at Miss Pierce's.
  - Hunt, Mary Ann (Wadhams), Mrs. Hiram, 1892 (Folder 56)
    Photograph of Mrs. Mary A. Hunt on her 100th birthday.
  - [empty] (Folder 57)
  - Knickerbocker, Caroline (Chester), Mrs. John Harman (Folder 58)
    Undated newspaper article with extracts from her 1815-1816 journal
  - Knickerbocker, Caroline (Chester), Mrs. John Harman (Folder 59)
    Undated photograph of Caroline Chester, 1801-1869.
  - Lewis, Jane, 1820 (Folder 60)
    "Journal for the summer of 1820"
  - Lewis, Jane R (Folder 61)
    Autograph album "Common Place Book" circa 1820 with one entry dated 1828.
  - Lewis, Jane R (Folder 62)
    Photocopy of circa 1820 autograph "Common Place Book"
  - Lewis, Marian, 1814-1836 (Folder 63)
    Autograph album started July 1814.
  - Masters, Susan (Folder 64)
    Bill for Miss Susan masters schooling. Payment received by S. Pierce. Susan was a student at Miss Pierce's in1805.
  - Masters, Susan (Folder 65)
    Photograph of Susan Masters at 53 from New Milford, Conn. Pupil at Miss Pierce's about 1805. Photograph from a portrait by Conlon of New Orleans.
  - McCracken, Cornelia E. (Tallmadge), Mrs. John, 1832 OCt 5 (Folder 66)
    Letter dated from Litchfield to her aunt, Mrs. Tomlindon in New York with news of life at school and in Litchfield.
  - Miner, Zervia R (Folder 67)
    Reward of merit - Class of good scholars. undated. Zervia was a student 1823-1827
  - Parmalee, Celeste [ia] (Folder 68)
    Litchfield Female Academy diploma. undated. Celeste was a student 1822-1826, 1829.
  - Perkins, Clarissa (Deming), Mrs. Charles, 1811 Apr 22 (Folder 69)
    Handwritten copy of judges report on Prize of Merit.
  - Phelps, Louisa C. (Lewis), Mrs. Henry, 1817 (Folder 70)
    Autograph album. Louisa was a student 1814-1818.
  - "Pink of the Pine Woods" (Folder 71)
    Undated letter to John P. Brace, signed "from his Sincere Friend, Pink of the Pine Woods"
  - Sanford, Amelia Selima (Folder 72)
    Litchfield Female Academy diploma, undated.
    Amelia was a student 1821-1824, 1827.
  - Sanford, Maria (Seymour), Mrs. Rollin (Folder 73)
    Litchfield Female Academy diploma, undated. Maria was a student 1824-1830.
  - Schroeder, Caroline M. (Boardman), Mrs. John F., 1815 (Folder 74)
    "Caroline M. Boardman's Journal Book, Litchfield, June 1st 1815"
  - Schroeder, Caroline M. (Boardman), Mrs. John F., 1815 (Folder 75)
    Transcript of her "Journal Book"
  - Shedden, Jane E, 1813 May 20 (Folder 76)
    Letter dated Norwalk to John P. Brace with news of her life and travels. Includes transcript.
  - Sheldon, Charlotte, 1796 (Folder 77)
    Diary 1796 May 10-July 22
  - Sheldon, Charlotte, 1976 (Folder 78)
    Transcript of her 1796 diary.
  - Tallmadge, Adeline (Mitchell), Mrs. Edwin (Folder 79)
    "Journal, Litchfield Connecticut" - first entry Friday, May 20th. undated
  - Tallmadge, Adeline (Mitchell), Mrs. Edwin (Folder 80)
    Transcript of "Journal, Litchfield, Conn."
  - Tallmadge, Adeline (Mitchell), Mrs. Edwin, 1820 (Folder 81)
    "Adeline Mitchell's Book, Litchfield, July 5th 1820". Autograph album 1820-1827.
  - Tallmadge, Catharine, 1835 Oct 12 (Folder 82)
    Receipt to Miss Catherine Tallmadge for Litchfield Female Seminary tuition. Signed by M.A. Swift.
  - Voorhees, Betsy (Reynolds), Mrs. Samuel, 1806-1807 (Folder 83)
    "Betsy Reynolds Journel for the year 1806 " first entry 3 Sep 1806 continues to 20 Jan 1807.
  - Voorhees, Betsy (Reynolds), Mrs. Samuel, 1806-1807 (Folder 84)
    Photocopy of "Betsy Reynolds Journel for the year 1806 " first entry 3 Sep 1806 continues to 20 Jan 1807.
  - Waterman, Delia (Storrs) Mrs. Thomas T., 1822 Aug 3 (Folder 85)